ANDREW KLEIN

Tucson, AZ • Klein.andrew26@gmail.com

GRADUATE STUDENT

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT, SCIENTIFIC INNOVATION

Accomplished and goal-driven graduate student at the University of Arizona in the Department of. Genetics. Graduated with a Bachelor of Science in Physiology and a minor in Biochemistry from the University of Arizona. Proven ability to evaluate, strategize, and conduct independent scientific experiments. Over hundreds of hours in clinical environments building clinical care skills. Self-starter, who takes the initiative, displays leadership and provides effective team support.

Areas of Expertise

Laboratory Technical Procedures | HIPAA Certified Accurate & Well-Organized Laboratory Records | Biological Laboratory Experimentation Research Strategy & Vision | Data-Driven Decision Making Team Development, Mentoring & Management

Technical Proficiencies

Microsoft Office Suite | Adobe Suite | DNA/RNA Extraction | PCR and RT-qPCR | Gel Electrophoresis Mammalian Cell Culture | iPSC Culture and Differentiation | Western Blot | Bacterial Cloning & Transformations | CRISPR | Drosophila Husbandry

> **Programming Languages** Python | R | Unix/Linux

Professional Experience

R. Ken Coit College of Pharmacy - Tucson, AZ

January 2023 – Present

Graduate Assistant

Pursuing a Genetics graduate degree in Dr. Jason Karnes' pharmacogenomics lab. Dr. Karnes is the Director of Scientific Programs for the AllofUs Research Program® allowing for this lab to have access to the AllofUs database. This lab uses clinical and genetic data to further our understanding of why some people have adverse reactions to widely used treatments. The aim is to further the field of precision medicine. My dissertation project will surround the HIT diagnosis that is common for patients taking the anti-coagulant Heparin.

- Producing publication quality figures using multiple coding languages.
- Processed patient samples for genetic analysis

Rotations during Graduate school - Tucson, AZ

Dr. Jared Churko' Lab and Dr. George Sutphin's Lab

- Hands-on experience with stem cell culturing and cellular imaging
- First experience with mouse work including dissection
- Hand-on experience with *C. elegans*, media prep, and imaging
- Learned multiple techniques to manipulate and manage C. elegans

Tucson Orthopedic Institute, -Tucson, AZ

September 2021 -August 2022

August 2022- December 2022

Medical Scribe

Accompany physicians into the patient examination room in order to transcribe a history and physical exam, and document accurately the physician's encounter with the patient and others present.

- Lists appropriate diagnoses and symptoms as well as follow-up instructions and prescriptions as dictated by the physician
- Document patient orders including laboratory tests, radiology tests, medications, etc.

- Interact comfortably with patients and current medical assistants to improve patient experience and expedite the efficiency of the clinic.
- Participated in many in-office surgeries

Arizona Cancer Center - Tucson, AZ

April 2018- August 2022

Research Technician I,

Assisting Dr. Keith Maggert and other researchers in his Drosophila lab. Promoted to a technician to spearhead many drosophila research projects. Received training in classical genetic work using Drosophila.

- Following basic lab and safety procedures
- Understanding of molecular biology, genetics, and fruit fly husbandry
- Received training in laboratory machines, protocols, devices, etc.

Tucson Medical Center - Tucson, AZ

May 2019- August 2019

Volunteer in the Intensive Care Unit

Assisted nurses and doctors in the cardiac and neurological ICU. Communicated with many new patients every day. Provided bedside manner to patients and assisted in minor medical procedures.

- Completed 100 hours of experience
- Appointed to respond appropriately in emergency situations
- Participated in patient care and administration of medications
- Engaged in hands-on experience in multiple medical procedures

Mama's Famous Pizza and Heroes - Tucson, AZ

July 2016- August 2021

Manager

A local family-owned pizza shop with multiple locations. Expectations are to deliver customer service in a fast-paced environment. Entrusted by the owners to run the shop and take responsibility for all employees and products that are being made.

- Collaborated with owners to make logistical decisions for many stores
- Worked multiple positions within the pizza shop
- Capable of maintaining relationships with colleagues
- Trained in food safety, restaurant health, and safety etiquette.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA, TUCSON, AZ, In Progress Ph.D., Department of Genetics GPA 4.0

THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA, TUCSON, AZ, 2021

Bachelor of Science, Physiology

Minor in Biochemistry

GPA 3.5

FIELDS OF STUDY

Biochemistry | Organic Chemistry | Cell and Developmental Biology Molecular and Cellular Genetics | Epigenetics | Pharmacogenetics | Bioinformatics | Clinical Genetics